Addison Emery Verrill Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Correspondence, 1864-1926; Series I
  - Rudolph Albert von Kolliker Correspondence. Correspondence from R.A. Kolliker to A.E. Verrill., 1867-1870; 001010
    - Rudolph Albert von Kolliker Correspondence. 8 letters from R.A. Kolliker to A.E. Verrill discussing Octocorallia and Hexacorallia research and exchanges., 24 Nov 1867 - 05 Jun 1870; 001011
  - Samuel Fessenden Clarke Correspondence. Correspondence from S.F. Clarke to A.E. Verrill., 1881; 001239
    - Samuel Fessenden Clarke Correspondence. A letter from S.F. Clarke to A.E. Verrill informing him he is sending specimens of American Amphioxus., 11 Jan 1881; 001240
  - Samuel Henshaw Correspondence. Correspondence from S. Henshaw to A.E. Verrill., 1886; 001276
    - Samuel Henshaw Correspondence. A letter from H. Henshaw inquiring about the presence of A.S. Packard type specimens in the collection. He encloses a list of the species he is interested in., 20 Nov 1886; 001277
  - Sanderson Smith Correspondence. Correspondence from S. Smith to A.E. Verrill., 1887-1892; 001130
    - Sanderson Smith Correspondence. A letter from S. Smith to A.E. Verrill telling him he has identified some of the shells from Verrill's sons trip to Dominica but is unable to do the rest. He suggests W.G. Binney or H.A. Pilsbry could do more., 03 Mar 1892; 001188
    - Sanderson Smith Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from S. Smith to A.E. Verrill discussing revisions to a manuscript. See Related Object in Associations tab., 26 Sep 1887; 001148
  - Spencer Fullerton Baird Correspondence. Correspondence from S.F. Baird to A.E. Verrill., 1880; 001104
    - Spencer Fullerton Baird Correspondence. A letter from S.F. Baird to A.E. Verrill inquiring on Anthozoa sent to Verrill for identification from off Georgetown County, South Carolina., 28 Jun 1880; 001105
  - Stephen Alfred Forbes Correspondence. Correspondence from S.A. Forbes to A.E. Verrill., 1879; 001134
    - Stephen Alfred Forbes Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from S.A. Forbes to A.E. Verrill discussing Hirudinea, and requesting to see Verrill's Semiscolex grandis. Note on envelope by Verrill, says "Forbes answered leech." See Related Object in Associations tab., 22 Aug 1879; 001157
  - T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. Correspondence from T.A. Verkruzen A.E. Verrill., 1877-1882; 001184
    - T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. A letter from T.A. Verkruzen. The letter is addressed to "the American Naturalists about to visit these seas". This refers to the arrival of the USFC Stmr. Speedwell to Halifax, Nova Scotia, of which Verrill was on board. He discusses his recent dredging work, and gives a list of specimens he left behind for them., 06 Aug 1877; 001185
    - T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. A letter from T.A. Verkruzen to A.E. Verrill thanking him for Verrill's paper of the Mollusca dredged by the USFC. He also discusses the Mollusca fauna of Newfoundland., 15 Sep 1882; 001187
    - T.A. Verkruzen Correspondence. A letter from T.A. Verkruzen to A.E. Verrill discussing the Mollusca fauna of Newfoundland and the Grand Banks. He inquires about the dredging work done by the USFC the summer before., 29 Mar 1881; 001186
  - Theodore Lyman Correspondence. Correspondence from Theodore Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing mostly Echinodermata, particularly Ophiuroidea., 1871-1882; 000943
    - Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing Ophiuroidea. Particularly Hemieuryale, Ophioplocus, Ophiochandrus, Trichaster, Astrogomphus, and Asteroschema., 07 Jan 1871; 001006
    - Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing nomenclature and also mentioning Hemipholis gracilis., 11 May 1872; 001007
    - Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing Ophiuroidea collected by USCS Stmr Blake. Particularly Asteronyx liveni and Ophioscolex. See Related Object in Associations tab., 13 Oct 1882; 001141
    - Theodore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman to A.E. Verrill discussing rules of nomenclature and asking Verrill for his works on Corals to aid in the identification of specimens in the Museum Godeffroy, Hamburg Germany., 22 Jul 1872; 001008
    - Theofore Lyman Correspondence. A letter from T. Lyman informing Verrill he has identified the Ophiuroidea that was sent and would like to keep one of the Hemieuryale in exchange. See Invoice Ledger., 19 Feb 1875; 001367
  - Ulysses S. Treat Correspondence. Correspondence from U.S. Treat to A.E. Verrill., 1863; 001307
    - Ulysses S. Treat Correspondence. A letter from U.S. Treat discussing alewifes and menhaden., 16 Dec 1863; 001309
    - Ulysses S. Treat Correspondence. A letter from U.S. Treat discussing his observations of "English Herrings" and Alewifes. He tells Verrill if it is of interest he may publish his observations if so desried., 29 Nov 1863; 001308
  - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. Correspondence from V.N. Edwards to A.E. Verrill., 1873-1881; 001111
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens. He lists localities and dates. See Invoice Ledger., 01 Mar 1878; 001375
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards to A.E. Verrill inforimg him that he is sending a squid for identification., 01 Nov 1881; 001112
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens, icluding fish and jellyfish. See Invoice Ledger., 02 Apr 1873; 001385
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending 2 jars of specimens. See Invoice Ledger., 03 Apr 1877; 001376
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of sponges from Nantucket Island. See Invoice Ledger., 06 Dec; 001380
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens. See Invoice Ledger., 06 Oct 1873; 001384
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens, inlcuding a gravid lobster, sponges and "sea fleas" (Amphipoda). See Invoice Ledger., 12 Jan; 001381
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens with a list of loaclities, inlcuding ascidians. See Invoice Ledger., 15 Dec 1875; 001382
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens and requests that Verrill identify them. See Invoice Ledger., 18 Mar 1874; 001383
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimenwith a list of localities. See Invoice Ledger., 21 Jan 1876; 001379
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens with a list of localities as well as a strange sea urchin with red spines. See Invoice Ledger., 26 Apr 1876; 001377
    - Vinal N. Edwards Correspondence. A letter from V.N. Edwards informing Verrill he is sending a box of specimens as well as something collected at Noman's Island.. See Invoice Ledger., 31 Mar 1876; 001378
  - W.A. Goodyear Correspondence. Correspondence from W.A. Goodyear to A.E. Verrill., 1885; 001296
    - W.A. Goodyear Correspondence. A letter from W.A. Goodyear inquiring about luminescence in insects., 12 Feb 1885; 001297
  - William Carmichael M'Intosh Correspondence. Correspondence from W.C. M'Intosh to A.E. Verrill., 1874; 001137
    - William Carmichael M'Intosh Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from W.C. M'Intosh to A.E. Verrill thanking him for the papers Verrill sent. See Related Object in Associations tab., 02 Jun 1874; 001160
  - William Healey Dall Correspondence. Correspondence from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill., 1882-1901; 001191
    - William Healey Dall Correspondence. A letter from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill discussing the difference between Ringicula leptocheila and Ringicula nitida., 01 Dec 1882; 001192
    - William Healey Dall Correspondence. A letter from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill thanking him for his Bermuda papers and discussing Mollusca from Bermuda., 17 Nov 1900; 001593
    - William Healey Dall Correspondence. A letter from W.H. Dall to A.E. Verrill thanking him for his Bermuda papers and discussing Cardium and other species of Bermuda specimens., 23 Jan 1901; 001594
  - William Stimpson Correspondence. Correspondence from W. Stimpson to A.E. Verrill., 1866; 001139
    - William Stimpson Correspondence. A transcribed copy of a letter from W. Stimpson to A.E. Verrill telling Verrill he has forwarded the specimens requested with a Smithsonian Institute package and asking him to return the bottles from Cape St. Lucas with the other things he borrowed. See Related Object in Associations tab., 21 Dec 1866; 001163
- Teaching Materials, 1864-1926; Series II
  Materials related to Verrill's professorship.
  - Notebooks., 002801
    - Notebook. Appears to be a class roster for Zoology and Geology courses. There are also notes about various species., 1864-1907; 001077
- Manuscript Materials, 1864-1926; Series III
  Rough drafts, figures, line drawings, etc. used in the writing of manuscripts and papers.
  - Annelida. Archives related to Verrill's Annelida manuscripts., 1864-1926; 001521
    - Annelida. Numerous notes and figures related to marine Annelida of Southern New England. Many used in his 1873 Report on marine invertebrates Vineyard Sound and Southern New England., 1864-1926; 001522
    - Annelida. Figures and notes of various Annelida. Mostly Southern New England. Labeled by Verrill as "used of incomplete.", 1864-1926; 001531
    - Annelida. Numerous copies of Plate 34, Trans. Conn. Acad. Arts. Sci. V. 4. Verrill, New England Annelids., 1864-1926; 001547
    - Annelida. 7 "plates" of Annelida. Labeled by Verrill as "Annelida Drawings Used.", 1864-1926; 001569
    - Annelida. Numerous pages of notes on scale worms (Polynoidae). Most in K.J. Bush handwritting, but many have annotations by Verrill., 1864-1926; 001634
    - Annelida. Notes on various species of annelida. Included are texts for plates and figures., 1877-1879; 001789
  - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Materials related to Verrill's unpublished manuscript on the Alcyonaria of the Blake Cruises., 1881-1926; 001793
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Plates 115-140. Some have notes by Verrill on them. Found together., 1881-1926; 001795
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Proofs of Plates 1-140. Numerous notes by A.E. Verrill on plates. Bound in 10 plate increments., 1881-1926; 001794
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 115, Dasygorgia., 1881-1926; 001796
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 116, Dasygorgia capitata, Riisea paniculata, 1881-1926; 001797
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 117, Dasygorgia spiculosa, Calliacis agassizii, Evacis rugulosa., 1881-1926; 001798
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 118, Dasygorgia., 1881-1926; 001799
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 119, Acanthacis austera, Echinacus armata., 1881-1926; 001800
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 120, Acanthacis austera., 1881-1926; 001801
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 121, Acanthacis scabra., 1881-1926; 001802
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 122., 1881-1926; 001803
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 123, Leptacis rubra, Scleracis pumila., 1881-1926; 001804
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 124, Muricea agassizii, Acromuricea multispina., 1881-1926; 001805
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 125, Echinacis clavata, Muricella (Cyclomuricea) flexuosa, Hyogorgia tenuis., 1881-1926; 001806
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 126, Scleracis, Scleracis petrosa, Thesacis verrucosa, Evacis rubra., 1881-1926; 001807
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 127, Paramuricea spinulosa, Acrogorgia muricata.., 1881-1926; 001808
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 128, Agrogorgia hirtella, Galaxacis microspina., 1881-1926; 001809
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 129, Hyogorgia parviflora., 1881-1926; 001810
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 130, Hyogorgia parviflora, Leptacis rubra., 1881-1926; 001811
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 131, Heteracis rudis, Heteracis mirabilis., 1881-1926; 001812
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 132, Evacis robusta, Evacis rugosa., 1881-1926; 001813
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 133, Evacis hebes, Evacis nivea., 1881-1926; 001814
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 134, Acanthogorgia exigua, Calicogorgia., 1881-1926; 001815
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 135, Acanthogorgia muricata, Cactomuricea setosa., 1881-1926; 001816
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 136, Aristogorgia, Aristogorgia ordinata., 1881-1926; 001817
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 137, Verrucella obesa., 1881-1926; 001818
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 138, Verrucella galaxea., 1881-1926; 001819
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 139, Stenogorgia gemmulata., 1881-1926; 001820
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. ~25 copies of Plate 140, Nephthyoides nigra, Acronephthya subinermis, Acronephthya spinosa, Chironephthya caribaea., 1881-1926; 001821
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. The plates were wrapped in a paper that has since disintegrated. They we labled "Blake Plates to be[?] stored attic O.K. by Dr. Van Name.", 1881-1926; 001822
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Figures, labeled by Verrill as "photo engravings.", 1881-1926; 001826
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Numerous figures, photographs and notes. Labeled by Verrill as "mostly photographs used for colored plates and Dupli.", 1881-1926; 001827
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Numerous figures, photographs and notes. Includes Muricidae and Chrysogorgia., 1881-1926; 001828
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Photographs and notes. Labeled by Verrill "used Photos....Muricidae Chrysogorgidae etc.", 1881-1926; 001829
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Drawings and proofs. Labeled by Verrill "used Drawings and proofs Foreign and native... for Canadian Report, U.S.F. Comm., etc. Pennatulacea, Alcyonacea, Nephthygidae, etc.", 1881-1926; 001830
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Photgraphs, figures. Labeled by Verrill "Blake Photos used.", 1881-1926; 001831
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Photgraphs. Labeled by Verrill "Photos mostly duplicates, used. Plexauridae, Pennatulidae, Primnoidae, Isidae, etc."", 1881-1926; 001832
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Notes, figures, proofs, text, etc., 1881-1926; 001833
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Notes, photographs and figures. Labeled by Verrill as "Chrysogorgidae, For Bulletin and text cuts. Radicipes type....", 1881-1926; 001834
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Plate proofs. Numerous notes by Verrill on them., 1881-1926; 001835
    - Blake Alcyonaria Manuscript. Plate proofs. Numerous notes by Verrill on them., 1881-1926; 001836
  - Bryozoa. Archives related to Verrill's manuscripts dealing with Bryozoa., 1864-1926; 001565
    - Bryozoa. Numerous photos, plates, figures and notes dealing with Bryozoa., 1864-1926; 001566
  - Cnidaria. A.E. Verrill manuscript materials related to Cnidaria., 1864-1926; 001501
    - Cnidaria. Stimpson notes for USNM 1571 (YPM No. 35762). From parent lot of IZAR No. 1638., 1853; 001759
    - Cnidaria. 6 figures of Cnidaria, including Pennatula aculeata and Iridogorgia pourtalesii., 1864-1926; 001502
    - Cnidaria. Figures and dictionary cutouts dealing with Hydroida., 1864-1926; 001503
    - Cnidaria. 15 figures, labeled by Verrill as "Radiates." Found in the same folder as IZAR No. 1531., 1864-1926; 001532
    - Cnidaria. Numerous figures and notes on Hydroida., 1864-1926; 001536
    - Cnidaria. Compilation of plates of Hydroida. They are bound together. Unknown what publication they were used in., 1864-1926; 001556
    - Cnidaria. List of Hydroida and Scyphozoa from Verrill's Report on Vineyard Sound., 1864-1926; 001564
    - Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of Actiniaria, labeled by Verrill as "used in 1864.", 1864-1926; 001568
    - Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of various Cnidaria, such as Edwardsia, Pennatula, etc., 1864-1926; 001635
    - Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of various Cnidaria of the North Pacific Exploring Expedition. The notes appear to be William Stimpson's. They contain a description and locality information with annotations by Verrill. Some include USNM numbers. Verrill used them in his papers on the Polyps of the North Pacific Exploring Expedition, published in the Proceedings of the Essex Institue, V. 5., 1864-1926; 001638
    - Cnidaria. Notes and sketches of various Cnidaria from F.H. Bradley's Expedition to central America. Labeled by Verrill as "Bradley notes on Radiata used", 1864-1926; 001639
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Edwardsia cretata Stimpson collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1617., 1864-1926; 002785
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Edwardsia clavata Stimpson [=Phellia? Clavata V. Mss.] collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1616., 1864-1926; 002786
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Urticina coccinea V. Mss. collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1583, 1864-1926; 002787
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Dysactis minuta V. Mss collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1570., 1864-1926; 002788
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Sagartia sp. V. collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1567, 1864-1926; 002791
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Metridium fimbriatum collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1592, 1864-1926; 002792
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Actinia multicolor Stimpson collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1613, 1864-1926; 002793
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Actinia like Metridium collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1579, 1864-1926; 002794
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Actinia nigropunctata Stimpson [=Sagartia nigropunctata mss] collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1611, 1864-1926; 002795
    - Cnidaria. Notes by William Stimpson pertaining to Discostoma fungiforme collected by N. Pac. Exploring Expedition, including subsequent annotations by A. E. Verrill. Specimen number 1564, 1864-1926; 002796
    - Cnidaria. Notes on Dendrophyllia gracilis (YPM No. 8476), 1864-1926; 002799
    - Cnidaria. Verrill's handwritten description of Paragorgia pacifica. It is attached to a photograph of the specimen sent by J.F. Whiteaves. See YPM No. 5373A-C., 001524
  - Crustacea of Connecticut. Archives realted to Verrill's unpublished manuscript titled "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters"., 1926; 001725
    - Crustacea of Connecticut. Rough draft of the "Bibliography" section for the "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters." According to a note by Verrill, he made an addittion of Rathbun's "Spider Crabs of America" on 15 Oct 1926., 001728
    - Crustacea of Connecticut. A typed copy of Verrill's unpublished manuscript titled "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters." Appears to have been edited, numerous notes were made., 1926; 001726
    - Crustacea of Connecticut. Rough draft of the "Explanations of Plates" section for the "Report on the Higher Crustace of Connecticut and Adjacent Waters.", 1926; 001727
  - Echinodermata. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Echinodermata., 1864-1926; 000947
    - Echinodermata. Photos and plates of Ophiuroidea and Asteroidea., 1864-1926; 001562
    - Echinodermata. 3 figures of Echinodermata (Crinoidea, Ophiuroidea). Also a figure of a Foraminifera. Labeled by Verrill as "Echinoderms unfinished.", 1864-1926; 001563
    - Echinodermata. 6 photos of Ophiuroidea., 1864-1926; 001567
  - Miscellaneous. A.E. Verrill manuscript material made up of multiple taxa., 1864-1926; 001506
    - Miscellaneous. Numerous figures, notes, etc. on numerous groups of organisms, inluding Mollusca, Cnidaria, Crustacea, Annelida, Echinodermata, etc. Many of which used in publications. Predominantly of Verrill, but includes material from Bush, Beecher, Clarke and Smith., 1864-1926; 001546
    - Miscellaneous. Notes, figures and descriptios of Cnidaria, Mollusca and Echinodermata. Found in same envelope., 1864-1926; 001548
    - Miscellaneous. Notes, figures and descriptions of Annelida, etc.., 1864-1926; 001551
    - Miscellaneous. Notes, locality data, specimen lists, etc. of various taxa. Labeled as "mostly used in first report.", 1864-1926; 001559
    - Miscellaneous. Numerous figures of sequentially numbered Echinodermata, Cnidaria, Mollusca etc. Unknown for what publication., 1864-1926; 001629
    - Miscellaneous. Numerous figures of developmental series., 1864-1926; 001631
    - Miscellaneous. A plate containing 3 figures of Tunicata and 2 figures of Gastropoda. A note by Verrill says "make same size.", 1864-1926; 001661
    - Miscellaneous. Many figures of Cnidaira, Echinodermata, etc. Used in Verrill, 1873. See Associations tab., 001662
    - Miscellaneous. A rough draft of plates for a publication on the fishes of Bermuda. Unknown if ever published. May have been done in conjunction with G.B. Goode. See Correspondence., 1900; 001664
    - Miscellaneous. A rough draft of "True Nature Stories for Boy Scouts." Was published posthumously in 1929. Includes duplicate chapters., 1926; 001672
    - Miscellaneous. Figures of multiple taxa. Including Gastropoda, Octopoda, etc. Found in association with one another in same folder., 001507
    - Miscellaneous. Figures of multiple taxa. Including mammals, birds, plants. Found in association with one another in same folder., 001508
    - Miscellaneous. Numerous figures, Eubranchipus vernalis, gastropoda etc. Also included are notes, many dealing with Radiata of Panama, etc., 001523
    - Miscellaneous. Numerous figures, notes and lists of Gastropoda, Annelida, Tunicata, etc. from the New England Coast., 001533
  - Mollusca. Verrill's manuscript materials related to Mollusca., 1864-1926; 000946
    - Mollusca. Figures and notes, labeled as "Mollusca, unfinished and imperfect, Deepwater and northern", by A.E. Verrill., 1864-1926; 001510
    - Mollusca. Figures and notes on Montacuta, Corbula and Clione., 1864-1926; 001511
    - Mollusca. 15 figures of Bivalvia. Labeled by Verrill as "used.", 1864-1926; 001512
    - Mollusca. 12 figures of Mollusca, mostly bivalves. Labeled by Verrill as "mostly used.", 1864-1926; 001513
    - Mollusca. Numerous figures and notes on the veliger of several species., 1864-1926; 001514